https://www.linkedin.com/in/chih-ho-chou-7012073/

# Chih-Ho Chou

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a seasoned and self-motivated software engineer who has extensive experience across various industries. My works span through backend, frontend, and platforms/infrastructures. My most recent work involves front-end performance tuning, web platform stability, and CI/CD improvements. I am a firm believer of picking the right tools and methodology to solve challenging problems.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Mostly C#, Java, and TypeScript/JavaScript; some
  Python and Go
- Front End: React, NexJS, Kendo, jQuery, and CSS
- Back End: GraphQL/Apollo Server and Relational/NoSQL DataBases
- CI/CD: Github Actions, Jenkins, and CircleCI
- Cloud: AWS, Terraform, and K8s/Dockers
- **Observability:** Sentry, DataDog, and Splunk
- Tools: Git/Github, Bash Shell, Vim/NVim

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Peloton Interactive, New York, NY - Software Engineer

February 2021 - PRESENT

- Onepeloton.com
  - Implemented page lazy-loading and used feature toggles to test components.
  - o Tools: React, styled components, storybook, and Optimizely
- Web platform
  - Nextjs incremental migration by building a hybrid CRA and Nextjs app.
  - DataDog integration with sourcemaps and custom tags for
    Observability. Used web hooks to communicate with other systems
    such as Slack and PageDuty based on events triggered.
- CI/CD
  - Refactored Github Action workflows with reusability and improved performance.
  - Redefined pre and post submit checks for better dev experience.
    Monitored and investigated pipeline health then find opportunities to improve health and performance of our CI/CD pipelines.

- Enterprise Messaging Hub
  - Commenced the work of building an organization-wide messaging hub with the Kafka based pub/sub architecture
- DevOps Transformation
  - Led the DevOps transformation for client by automating build processes
  - Based on feedback gathered from different parts of the organization, defined end to end for CI pipelines

#### TEKSystems, New York, NY - Software Contractor

August 2016 - October 2017

- Global Technology Infrastructure, J. P. Morgan Chase
  - Led the pilot .NET CORE project and shared learnings and pros and cons
  - Refactored the Data Access Layer to be generic by using Repository with unit of work pattern

## IntegriData, New York, NY - Senior Software Engineer

October 2015 - August 2016

- Restful Web API integration for client to consume our product, CashWire
- Implemented configurable approval workflows for vendor invoicing system
  .NET MVC, EntityFramework, and Kendo UI

## The Segal Group, New York, NY - Application Developer

November 2013 - October 2015

- Ref360.com
  - Worked as a lead developer to gather requirements and implement scalable solutions with object-oriented and test-driven principles in mind
  - Refactored front end data binding with knockout.js to move toward a single page application model.

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Developer Associate (Certified: Oct 2019)
- MCSD (Microsoft Certified Solution Developer) Web Applications (Certified: Sept. 2016)
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist .NET Framework 4, Web Applications
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist .NET Framework 3.5

### **EDUCATION**

## New York University, New York, NY - MS, Computer Science

September 2002 - May 2005